<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Everyday Normal Geek]]></title><description><![CDATA[Everyday Normal Geek]]></description><link>http://everydaynormalgeek.com</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 13:21:03 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://everydaynormalgeek.com/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[Intellij plugin to support Pony]]></title><description><![CDATA[<div class="paragraph">
<p>I&#8217;m a Java/Scala developer and I am used to Intellij Idea for my work. When I started my interest in Pony, I used Sublime Text for a short while and then switched to Atom for code highlighting. But what I miss
in both these tools are all the information that Intellij provides - code completion, inspection, refactoring, analysis.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>I decided to start my own Intellij plugin to support Pony language on that platform. There is a <a href="http://www.jetbrains.org/intellij/sdk/docs/index.html" class="bare">http://www.jetbrains.org/intellij/sdk/docs/index.html</a>	[nice tutorial] on adding new language support for Intellij so I started with the basics and hit a wall. This tutorial mentions using the GrammarKit plugin which generates a lot of boilerplate from BNF grammars. The issue I had was that the grammar file in Pony repository was Antlr v3 grammar and I spent a few days investigating how to convert one to another. After some unsuccessful attempts I had to postpone work on this little project.</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>Today I was playing with Pony and noticed this small line in the output of <code>ponyc --help</code> - <code>--bnf Print out the Pony grammar as human readable BNF.</code> I was shocked - I don&#8217;t know when this was implemented (current Pony version is 0.1.7) but it saves the plugin development! It still wasn&#8217;t the format expected by GrammarKit plugin but it was very easy to adapt. After a few moments I had a grammar file with generated tokens and all stuff required by the parser!</p>
</div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>That&#8217;s just one small step towards the first version of the plugin. The features I&#8217;d like to have in the very first published version are: syntax highlighting, pony files support, run configuration to build the project.
This would allow people to start developing Pony applications from within Intellij. There&#8217;s still a lot of work to do, so any help is appreciated. The project is located in <a href="https://github.com/pbuda/intellij-pony">this GitHub repository</a>. Fork away!</p>
</div>]]></description><link>http://everydaynormalgeek.com/2016/08/05/Intellij-plugin-to-support-Pony.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://everydaynormalgeek.com/2016/08/05/Intellij-plugin-to-support-Pony.html</guid><category><![CDATA[Pony]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Intellij]]></category><category><![CDATA[ Plugin]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[Piotr Buda]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>